# Joe Pauker

www.linkedin.com/in/joe-pauker

South Plainfield, NJ 07080

joe.pauker@live.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a flexible, self-motivated student with excellent knowledge in software programming, leadership, industry, and customer service. Prior to voluntarily stepping down to pursue a career change I spent over five years as a manager where I gained extensive knowledge in customer satisfaction as well as time, project, and employee management.

#### **EDUCATION**

Kean University, Union, NJ GPA: 3.77 Expect Graduation May 2020

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science, Minor Mathematics

Triangle Tech, Bethlehem, PA GPA: 4.00 Graduated 2010

Associates Degree in Specialized Technology, Carpentry and Construction Technology

#### COURSE WORK

Data Structures, Computer Organization and Programming, Discrete Systems, Database Management, Computer Architecture, Assembly Language, Linear Algebra, Intro to Proofs, Data Visualization

#### TECHINICAL SKILLS

Java, Assembly Language, HTML, PHP, MySQL, CCS, JavaScript, C, ¡Query

#### **PROJECTS**

**Data Visualization** 

September 2019-December 2019

- Create a website using MySQL, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX methods, PHP and CCS that will allow the user to upload a data file or retrieve from database and translate the data into various graphs. It also shows how different data and programming languages can interact.
- Project Link: <a href="http://eve.kean.edu/~paukerj/CPS4745/">http://eve.kean.edu/~paukerj/CPS4745/</a>

Online Banking February 2019-May 2019

- Design a mock online banking system coded with PHP, HTML and MySQL. The Project utilized PHP and MySQL skills such as creating tables, insert, delete, and select statements
- Project Link: <a href="http://eve.kean.edu/~paukerj/CPS3740/">http://eve.kean.edu/~paukerj/CPS3740/</a>

#### **Database Functions and Procedures**

April 2019-May 2019

Created a variety of functions and procedures using MySQL to search a database and display results and/or tables. Program displayed a
message in the event of an error or indicated that no results were found.

Online Banking Design March 2019-May 2019

Object-Oriented Design, collaborative, group project to create and design an online banking system. Developed a customer proposal to
include business analysis, use cases diagrams, UML diagrams, communication diagrams, and user interfaces. An oral presentation was
completed to present the project.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Code Samurai September 2019-Present

Volunteer Computer Science tutor, specializing in database (MySQL), PHP, Javascript and basic Java skills

### Part-time Customer Service Associate, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

September 2017-Present

- Ensure customers have a high-level shopping experience by utilizing five years of management experience to ultimately help the company to continue to succeed.
- Trained new management to streamline the integration and transition process

# Back-End Support Manager, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

January 2017-September 2017

- Managed 20+ employees, across 5 departments, at a \$28million store
- Ensured groups consistently maintained high performance standards by resolving customer and employee conflicts when they arose.

## Department Manager, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

March 2013-January 2017

- Oversaw biannual, full department, floor resets for spring and winter season
- Maintained departments with weekly store updates to meet and exceed overall sales and customer service experience
- Reviewed weekly sales plans, vital stats and operational reports to oversee the overall department progress and inform associates and upper management with weekly store updates

#### Delivery and Receiving Associate, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

March 2012-March 2013

• Coordinated the receiving and delivery of company product, customer service and maintenance

## HONORS AND ACHEIVEMENTS

- Kean University: Dean's List: 2017 Fall | 2018 Spring, Summer and Fall | 2019 Spring
- Triangle Tech: High Honors: all four semesters
- Lowe's: Mid-Year Employee Excellence Award: Summer 2018
- Lowe's: Manager of the Quarter: February 2015, June 2016
- Lowe's: Excellent Employee Award: 6 times over the past 6 years